Guide to the Louis Napoleon Parker Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Writings, 1869-1941.
  - Riposte! (Francillon). A Play in Three Acts by Alexandre Dumas, fils, Adapted by Parker, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - A Rogue's Wife. A Play in Three Acts by Parker, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Rosemary, That's For Remembrance. A Comedy in Four Acts by Parker and Murray Carson, 1895 June 16 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Rosemary. "New Epilogue," 1902 May 27 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Rosemary. Act IV, 1903 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Rosemary. Prompt copies: William, Abraham, Miss Minifie, Mrs. Cruikshank, Sir Jasper Thorndike, Crowd, Captain Cruikshank, Priscilla (Act II), Dorothy Cruikshank, Professor Jogram, Waiter, George Minifie, Stilt-Walker, 1902-1903 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - The Scarament of Judas. A Play in Three Acts by Louis Tiercelin. Translated by Parker, [1899] (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - The Sacrament of Judas. A Play in Three Acts by Louis Tiercelin. Translated by Parker, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - "The Sad Case of Mrs. Bundock," undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - The Scoffer. A Thirteenth Century Dramatic Farce in Four Acts by Nino Berrini. Translated by Parker, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - The Sea Robber. A Comedy in Four Acts by Ludwig Fulda. Freely Translated by Parker, 1913 February 12 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - The Shipbuilder. A Play in Four Acts by Parker, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Shocks. A Story by Algernon Blackwood. Retold in dialogue by Parker. St. Valentine's Day 1941 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Sir Lancelot of the Lake. A Play in Five Acts by Parker, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - The Smiling Dawn. A Play in Four Acts, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - The Sparrow. A Comedy in Four Acts, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - The Stepney Children's Pagent (Prologue), undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Summer Is A Comin' In (alternate title Summertime ). A Comedy in Three Acts, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - The Swashbuckler, A Romantic Farce in Four Acts, [1900] (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - The Syren. An Original Play in Three Acts, 1894 January 29 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - That Mrs. Winslowe. A Story by Algernon Blackwood. Retold as a Comedy in Two Scenes, 1941 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Trifles Light As Air, 1887-1941 (Box 20)
  - Tristan and Isolde. Wagner. Roughly translated for the benefit of the Parsifal Pilgrims, 1886 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - The Turmoil. A Play in Three Acts by A.I. Theix. Adapted by Parker, 1891 October 26 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - The Twin Sisters. A Comedy in Four Acts by Ludwig Fulda. Parker, 1901 October 14 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - The Two Miss Romains. A Play in Three Acts by Marguerite Allotte de La Fuÿe, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - The Two Queens. The Story of the Play, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Untitled Manuscripts, undated, 1924-1932 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - The Vagabond King. A Play in Four Acts by Parker, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - The Vicar of Wakefield. By Oliver Goldsmith. Made into a Play in Five Acts by Parker, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - The Wages of Sin. A Play in Four Acts. (Founded on the Novel) by Lucas Malet and Parker, undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - The Walled Garden. Words for Music, 1931 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - The Werewolf. A Tale by Algernon Blackwood. Dramatized by Parker, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - The Wild Colleen. A Comedy in Three Acts by Parker, 1915 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - A Woman's Battle. A Play in Three Acts. By Maurice Soulié and Louis Marsolleau. Adapted by Parke, 1904 (Box 21, Folder 10)
- Series IV: Other Professional Work, 1907-1937
  This series contains printed material of various genres produced by or used by Parker, including the financial records of three productions and the property plot for one play, sheet music, typescripts of plays in French, and newspaper clippings.
  - Financial records: "Balance Sheet, Bury, Warwick," 1907 Disraeli, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - "Louis N. Parker's Plays Available for the Screen," undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Lourdes: Property plot, undated, and Library of Congress registration card, 1917 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Subseries IV.1: Sheet music, undated
    This sub-series includes three pieces of music by Parker; “Hunting Song” and A Pageant Dance are in fair condition; one untitled piece is in poor condition, and so is fragmentary.
    - "Hunting Song," undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - A Pagent Dance (oversized), undated (Box 14-L-1)
    - Untitled (had been loosely placed in One Act Plays, I.) (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Subseries IV.2: Theater-related Materials, undated, 1918
    Included here are typescripts of French plays by Marguerite Allotte de la Fuÿe and Victorien Sardou and Emile Moreau, which Parker may have intended to translate at some point. There is also a large file of newspaper clippings related to the 1918 libel suit brought by the actress and dancer Maud Allan against Noel Pemberton Billings, regarding public accusations made about Allan’s sexual orientation and political allegiances arising from her appearance in a London production of Oscar Wilde’s Salomé. This file contains an unsigned, undated typed article or speech about the trial and its outcome, possibly authored by Parker.
    - de la Fuÿe, Marguerite Allotte. Bethsabee, undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Sardou, Victorien and Emile Moreau. Mdme Tallien, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Noel Pemberton Billings libel trial file, 1918 (Box 22, Folder 9)
- Series V: Programs, Clippings and Posters, 1889-1939
  Theater programs for productions of nearly all of Parker’s plays are included in this series, as well as newspaper clippings (generally contemporary reviews). The programs are arranged alphabetically by play title; the names of the theaters that staged the productions are included in the finding aid entry after the play title. The production titles of several plays differ from those Parker originally gave them; in such cases the programs are filed according to Parker’s title, with alternate titles indicated in parentheses.
  - Actors' Church Union Hostel Memorial Appeal Matinee: Bristol Hippodrome, 1918 October 26 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Agatha: His Majesty's Theatre, 1905 March 6-7 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - L'Aiglon: Knickerbocker Theatre and The Globe Theatre, 1900, 1918 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Angelo (alternate title Johannes Kreisler ): Theatre Royal Drury Lane, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - The Aristocrat, 1922 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Beauty and the Barge: Wallack's; Daz Herz Auft Der Hand, 1913 (Box 14-L-1)
  - The Blue Boar: Terry's Theatre and Royal Court Theatre Liverpool, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - The Brighter Side Knickerbocker Theatre, 1905 February 6 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - The Bugle Call: Theatre Royal Haymarket, 1899 November 23 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Buried Talent: St. Anselm's, Streatham, 1891 November 24-25 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Bury St. Edmund's Pageant, "Woeful Ballad of King Sweyn," 1907 July 8-13 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - The Cardinal: Princess Theatre, Academy of Music, Garden Theatre, St. James's Theatre London, Opera House Tunbridge Wells, Bristol's Little Theatre, Pavilion Theatre Weymouth, Teatro Manzoni, undated, 1901-1904, 1926, 1931 (Box 14-L-1)
  - Change Alley: Garrick Theatre, 1899 April 25 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Chanticleer: Theatre de le Porte Saint-Martin and Knickerbocker Theatre, 1910-1911 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - "Chris" (alternate titles A Broken Life and Captain Birchell's Luck ): Vaudeville Theatre, Grand Theatre London, The Grand Theatre Islington, Terry's Theatre, 1892-1899 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - The Compleat Angler (alternate titles Gudgeons and "Wonderful James!" ) Garrick Theatre, Terry Theatre, Empire Theatre, New Grand Theatre, (Includes ink drawing by Arthur Devitt), 1893-1897 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - David: The Garrick Theatre, The Daily Programme, Terry's Theatre, Royal Court Theatre Liverpool, 1892-1894 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - David Garrick (alternate title Mr. Garrick: Royal Court Theatre, 1922 September 29 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Disraeli: Metropolitan Theatre, Knickerbocker Theatre, 1914-1917 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - The Dover Pageant: 25th anniversary, 1933 January 13 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Drake: York and London Coliseum, 1916, 1939 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - The Duel: Hudson Theatre, 1906 February 19 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - An English Nosegay: Apollo Theater, undated (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Everybody's Secret and The Creole: Theatre Royal Haymarket, 1905 March-May (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - The Happy Life: Duke of York's Theatre, Parkhurst Theatre, Terry's Theatre, The Alpha Literary and Dramatic Club, undated, 1900 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Harlequin (alternate title Arlequin ): Empire Theatre, 1922 December 21 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - The Heel of Achilles: Globe Theatre, undated (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - The Highway of Life (alternate title David Copperfield ): His Majesty's Theatre, Wallack's Theatre, 1914. (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - The House of Burnside: Terry's Theatre, 1904 April 28 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - The Jest: Criterion Theatre, 1888 November 10 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Joseph and His Brethren: St. Mary's Catholic Amateur Dramatic Society, undated (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - King Henry (alternate title Bluff King Hal: Garrick Theatre, 1914 September 4 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - The Lady of Coventry: Royal Alexandria Theatre, Princess Theatre Montreal, Daly's Theatre, 1911 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - The League of Nations, 1919 November 8 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - The Lord of Death: The New Theatre, 1924 April 6-13 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Lourdes: King's Hall at Covent Garden, 1921 April 9 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Love in a Mist: Digby Hotel Gardens, 1891 July (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Love in Ildeness: Theatre Royal Brighton, Terry's Theatre, 1896-1902 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Magda: Grand Theatre Fulham, Royal Lyceum Theatre, undated, 1896 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - La Main de Singe, undated (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - The Man in the Street: Avenue Theatre, 1894 April 21 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - The Masque of War and Peace, undated (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Mavourneen: His Majesty's Theatre, undated (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - The Mayflower: Lyceum Theatre New York, 8 The Green Room (Amateur Dramatic Society Liverpool), Theatre Metropole Camberwell, Lyceum Theatre New York, Theatre Royal Edinburgh, undated, 1897-1907. (Box 24)
    Poster for the Theatre Metropole production located in Map Case 14-L-1
  - Monsieur D'Artagnan: Chelsea Palace Theatre, undated (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Mr. George and "Jemmy": Vaudeville Theatre, 1907 April 25 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Once Upon a Time: Theatre Royal Haymarket, undated (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Orpheus: Warwick Castle, July 1922 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Our Nell: Gaiety Theatre, 1924 April 16 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - A Pageant of Fair Women: Chiswick Theatre, 1917 May (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Pete: Lyceum Theatre, 1908 August 29 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Pomander Walk: Wallack's Theatre, Majestic Theater Brooklyn, Plymouth Theatre Boston, Concord Players (MA), 1911, 1926 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Queen Victoria, undated (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Ragged Robin: Her Majesty's Theatre, 1898 June 23 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - The Right Hand of the Prince: King's Theatre Hammersmith, undated (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Rosemary, That's for Remembrance: Empire Theatre, Hollis St. Theatre, 1896-1897 (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - The Sacrament of Judas: Comedy Theatre, undated (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - The Sequel: Vaudeville Theatre, undated (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Sherborne Abbey Tower Restoration Fund Concert, [1884] May 27 (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - The Sherborne Pageant, undated (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - The Stepney Children's Pageant, undated (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - The Tame Cat: The Assembly Rooms, Putney, 1893 January 19 (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - The Termagant: Her Majesty's Theatre, Wallack's Theatre, 1898-1899 (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - The Treasures of Britain: The Shaftesbury Theatre, 1917-1918 (Box 24, Folder 33)
  - The Twin Sisters: Empire Theatre, 1902 March 31 (Box 24, Folder 34)
  - Typho: Village Hall, Esher, 1921 March 30 (Box 24, Folder 35)
  - The Warwick Pageant: Souvenir book, Warwick Musical Society, 1906, 1935 (Box 24, Folder 36)
  - "Yes or No?" undated (Box 24, Folder 37)
  - Programs for Plays by Others, undated, 1923-1924 (Box 24, Folder 38)
- Series VI: Photographs, 1876-1933
  This small series consists of photographs of locations, of groups and individuals including de la Fuÿe, Henry Irving, Richard Mansfield, Frédéric Mistral, and Parker’s daughter Dorothy, an actress. Photographs (and some photo-postcard drawings) related to several of Parker’s plays and pageants are also included.
  - Locations (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - People: Groups and Individuals (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Productions, B-M: Bury St. Edmund's Pageant; The Grove Pageant; The Happy Life; Jacob and His Brethren; The Masque of War and Peace. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Productions, Q-W: Queen Victoria; The Stepney Children's Pageant; The Warwick Pageant. (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Series VII: Books, 1881-1937
  These are mostly presentation copies given to Parker by friends and admirers; most are inscribed. A notable exception is Parker’s copy of Shakespeare’s Henry VIII, heavily annotated by Parker, including suggested cuts for performance and illustrations indicating blocking and scene designs.
  - Child, Harold. Hugh, the Drover, Or Love in the Stocks, 1937. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Fraser-Simson, Harold. The Maid of the Mountains, A Musical Play in Three Acts, 1914. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Rhoades, James A., trans. The Georgics of Virgil, 1881. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Rogers, Sanders. Guyde de Booke offe ye "Merrie England Fayre and Markyette," with ye Wordes of ye Pageant ate ye Grove to Aide ye Christ Church Funds, 1912 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Shakespeare, William. King Henry VIII, 1894 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Young, Edward M. Apis Matina, Verses Translated and Original, 1900 (Box 25, Folder 10)